Tanvi Sachdeva

Full Stack

Contact

Address

Pune, India, 411057

Phone

916 858 8710

E-mail

sachdevatanvi2311@gmail.c om

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sachdevatanvi2311/

www

https://tanvisachdeva.githu b.io/tanviprofile.html

Skills

Javascript

Angular

.NET Full Stack

Scrum

Agile

C#

Leadership and Management

Azure

Project Management

Typescript

8+ years of experience in leading and managing project delivery with significant experience as an individual contributor.

Tech stack - JavaScript, typescript, Angular, .NET, C#, WebApi, React, Agile and Azure AZ900 certified and more than willing to upskill in newer technologies should the project require. Have international experience of working in France on client side.

Work History

2022-04 -Current

Full Stack Lead

Accenture India

- WebApi, C#, Typescript, React, Redux, Balsamiq, GIT, Adobe XD, Google cloud, object oriented programming, Agile, Scrum ceremonies
- Develop, build, review and test frontend and backend software solutions and work with other developers and businesses to propose high-quality solutions to meet business goals.
- Confident in working independently or in a team in a deadline driven environment with quality deliverables.
- Strong communication and organizational skills with an ability to thrive in a fast-paced production deadline-driven environment both internal and client facing.
- Ability to solve complex development problems and produce the highest quality code while striving to push technical boundaries of online applications
- Ability to work quickly while maintaining strong attention to detail and accuracy while adhering to W3C and accessibility guidelines.
- Strong attention to detail and understanding of UI concepts to provide perspective on front and backend technologies and their overall impact on the creative process.

2019-06 -2022-04

Technical Lead

Sopra Steria India Limited

 Client - European multinational aerospace leader (Have international experience of working in France on client side) HTML

CSS

Mongodb

SQL

Object Oriented Programming

React

Algorithms

- Javascript, Angular, .NET Webapi, Agile, GIT, IIS, Mongodb
- Lead and performed end to end delivery of web applications starting from requirement understanding to implementation to deployment.
 Contribute to end-to-end codebase of application including rich frontend, thoughtful web APIs, and well-designed databases
- Participate in all scrum ceremonies. Closely worked with Product owners/client/business in scoping and estimation of user stories during PI planning.
- Mentored junior team members who are on a technical career path and are interested in becoming future technical leads and engineers.

2018-06 -2019-06

Lead Engineer

HCL Technologies Limited

- Client American multinational technology leader
- ASP.net MVC, GIT, Azure, jQuery, Ajax, JavaScript, CSS
- Investigating bugs in software application based on technical expertise and developing solutions in accordance with quality accredited standards.
- Mentored team members on technical front so that quality code is delivered with minimal postproduction bugs/issues.
- Full understanding of web Accessibility including knowledge of WCAG 3.0
- Effectively manage scope and client expectations on individual assignments.
- Work with Agile team to deliver applications iteratively, and incorporate feedback into future iterations.

2015-08 -2018-04

Product Integration Engineer

EdgeVerve Systems Limited

- Client American multinational telecom leader
- .NET MVC, SQL, Jquery, Javascript, Angular
- Analyze business problems, develop technology solutions to those problems and manage project through its lifecycle.

- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Providing timely deliverables to client, solving post production bugs/issues were handled.

2014-09 -2015-07

Systems Engineer

Infosys Limited

- Client American multinational telecom leader
- Full stack developer
- C#, .NET, Angular JS, SQL

Education

2010-08 -2014-07

Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science And Engineering

Rajasthan Technical University
My bachelor's is equivalent to 4 years Canadian
Bachelor's degree certified through Education
Credential Assessment done by University of Toronto

Certifications

2021-05	AZ-900 Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals
2021-06	AZ-104 Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator